## Abhishek Sharma

abhisheksharma.nith@gmail.com +91-70499-21552

https://linkedin.com/in/abhishek-sharma-9289a965/ https://shar-abhi.github.io/

## SENIOR, II SDET

A Test Engineer bringing ~7 years of relevant experience, having previously worked in domains such as CDN and Cloud security. I, strive to provide a comprehensive and effective testing strategy by critically analysing the system, aiming to prevent unseen workflows in production which prove to be a hassle to the customer and company.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Akamai 2022 - Present

Senior II SDET (2024 - Present) Senior SDET (2022 - 2024)

- Enhanced end-to-end automation coverage using frameworks like Selenium/Pytest/Unittest, boosting the automation of feature testcases and reducing the regression time by ~83% from 24hrs to 4hrs.
- Worked on ~2-3 production issues per month, using my subject matter expertise of the project, coordinating and bridging the workflow between Customer/Ops to Devs for identification, replication and deployment of fixes for such issues.
- Automated 250+ test cases and 5+ custom libraries for our project automation, maintaining reusability of commonly
  used functionality, ensuring ease of automation for everybody in future test case automation.
- Led design, execution and automation of testing strategies for multiple features, having written test strategies for more
  than 10 project critical features dealing with improving request to cache-hit ratio within a multi hop architecture, load
  spreading of client requests, enhancing disk utilisation etc.

Zscaler 2019 - 2022

Senior Software Engineer (2022) Software Engineer (2019 - 2022)

- Responsible for testing efforts of critical production features such as SSL, Bandwidth Control, and MTS Infrastructure, from test plan design to implementation using various testing methodologies and automating the same.
- Led efforts to transition automation from Perl to Python as well as develop and maintain a custom test framework based on the Pytest module of Python.
- Implemented Jenkins CI/CD pipelines to automate testing stages, reducing timelines and minimizing human intervention.
- Conducted performance testing using Spirent, automating performance test suites with Python and Jenkins pipelines for seamless execution.
- Investigated customer escalations by recreating issues and collaborating with developers to pinpoint and resolve them.

State Bank of India 2017 - 2019

Assistant Manager (P.O)

Managed day-to-day operations of a bank branch, with an aim at providing exceptional customer service and resolving
issues promptly leveraging my IT know-how to enhance customer service delivery within the bank branch.

Zscaler 2013 - 2015

## Junior Software Engineer

- Automated functional UI test cases using Selenium framework in Java.
- Built & maintained the in-home regression management system Z-ARMS using Java, Javascript and Bash.
- Conducted manual testing for regression and sanity checks on various features.

**EDUCATION** 

NIT Hamirpur 2009 - 2013

B. Tech in Computer Science and Engg.

**SKILLS** 

Scripting: Python, Perl, Javascript, Bash Tools: Docker, Jenkins, JMeter, Spirent, curl, openssl

Manager to the Day of the COVAL

Frameworks: Pytest, Unittest, Selenium, Locust

Version control: Git, Perforce, SVN